Guide to the Alpha Delta Phi Records, 1832 - 2017
Alpha Delta Phi Records 1832 - 2017
- Series VIII: Members, 1852-2011
  - Personal Realia
    - Littell, Frank Bowers
      These items consist of a pin and email correspondence regarding the acquisition of an ADP pin of Frank Littell, class of 1891. Found within the email correspondence is a brief biography on Littell.
      - Email correspondence & bio, 2010 (Box 167, Folder 4)
      - ADP pin, 1891 (Box 167, Folder 5)
- Series IX: Memorabilia 1959-2003
  Materials for this series are housed in five oversize boxes, 3.5 linear feet.
  - Oversize, Posters, [1959-1988] (Box 207)
  - Oversize, T-shirts (Box 209-212)
    These t-shirts are tie-dyed pledge shirts, basic APD logo shirts and shirts from International or Society conventions. The shirts have been grouped dated and undated and are arranged in chronological order when dates are provided.
- Series X: Photographs
  Includes photographs and negatives of Alpha Delta Phi members, places, and events. When photographs were found within other series, the photographs were removed from those files and placed in Series X: Photographs. A separation sheet was inserted where the items were removed to note what was moved and to where. When possible, groups of photographs were kept together and labeled accordingly, i.e. House & Property, Members. Materials for this series are housed in three document boxes and two oversize boxes, 3.6 linear feet.
  - 1870s-1980s (Box 167, Folder 6-11)
  - 1980s-1990s (Box 169, Folder 1-2)
  - Archivist's Files, Digital Photos (Box 169, Folder 3)
  - Chines Food Cannery (Box 169, Folder 4)
  - Contact sheets & negatives (Box 169, Folder 5)
  - Conventions (Box 169, Folder 6)
  - House & Property
    - 1884 House (Box 169, Folder 7)
    - 1904 House
      - undated, 1906-2000s (Box 169, Folder 8-14)
      - Oversize1906, 1914 (Box 207)
      - Aerial, 2010 (Box 169, Folder 15)
      - Renovations
        - 1978 (Box 169, Folder 16)
        - Front Porch Project, 2005 (Box 169, Folder 17-18)
        - Front Porch Project, 2005 (Box 170, Folder 1-2)
        - Front Porch Project, recently completed work at the House, 2005 (Box 170, Folder 3)
        - Front Porch Project, work that still needs to be done at the House, 2005 (Box 170, Folder 4)
  - Members
    - A-Z (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - Kowalski, Carl & Evelyn (Box 170, Folder 6-10)
  - (Box 171)
    These photographs are either 3x5 or 4x6 and are mostly undated and unidentified.
  - Oversize, unidentified (Box 207)
- Series XI: Society 1992-2014
  These files consist of the records created after the Middletown Chapter left the International and joined the Society. Materials include constitution, convention records, correspondence, and publications. Materials for this series are housed in four document boxes, 1.7 linear feet.
  See also Series IV: Co-Educational Issue.
  - Address List, 1998-2000 (Box 166, Folder 18-19)
  - Birth of (1992) (Box 166, Folder 20)
  - Chapters
    - Misc. (Box 166, Folder 21)
    - Columbia, Pledge Manual, 1993 (Box 166, Folder 22)
    - Letters (Box 166, Folder 23)
    - Penn (Box 166, Folder 24)
    - Tufts (Box 166, Folder 25)
  - Constitution (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Constitution Draft, 1997 (Box 172, Folder 2)
  - Conventions
    - 1993-2003 (Box 172, Folder 3-11)
    - 2003-2013 (Box 173, Folder 1-10)
    - 2013 (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Xaipe Newsletter (Box 174, Folder 2)
- Series XII: Songbooks 1859-2012
  This series includes songs & songbooks for Alpha Delta Phi and for Wesleyan University. Materials for this series are housed in three document boxes and two custom boxes, 3 linear feet.
  - Alpha Delta Phi
    - 1859-1912 (Box 174, Folder 3-10)
    - undated (Box 175, Folder 1-2)
    - Adelphic Airs, undated (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - undated, [1965]-1991 (Box 175, Folder 4-7)
    - Official Alpha Delta Phi Christmas Carols, 1997 December (Box 175, Folder 8)
    - 2004-2012 (Box 175, Folder 9-13)
    - Coed Song (transparencies) (Box 175, Folder 14)
    - The Songs of Alpha Delta Phiundated (Box 176)
      The Songs of Alpha Delta Phi was originally released as a set of three 78 RPM records. Unfortunately, no date is printed on the record labels, so we do not know when these recordings were made. Because the lyrics of We Come With A Shout And A Song require the singers to insert the name of their college, we know that the performers are from the Cornell chapter. The authors, where known, are listed as they appear in the Song Book of Alpha Delta Phi published in 1912.
  - Wesleyan University
    - Wesleyan Sings 1928-1962, 2008 (Box 177, Folder 1)
      Contains CDs.
    - Wesleyan Songs, undated (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - The Wesleyan Song Book, 1901 (Box 177, Folder 3-4)
    - The Wesleyan Song Book, 1914 (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - Wesleyan Song Book, 1940 (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - Wesleyan Song Book 1940 (proposal to reprint), 1994 (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - Reunion Songbook, 1997 (Box 177, Folder 8-9)
    - All College Sing, 1998 (Box 177, Folder 10)
    - Wesleyan Song Book, 2000 (Box 177, Folder 11)
    - undated (Box 178)
- Series XIII: Wesleyan 1946-2014
  The records in this series document the relations, agreements, and events between Wesleyan University and the Alpha Delta Phi Middletown Chapter or more generally fraternities on campus represented by the Board of House Presidents. Items include correspondence, meeting minutes, reports, event programs and invitations, and newspaper clippings. Materials for this series are housed in two document boxes, .83 linear feet.
  - Wesleyan & Greek Housing, 2014 (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - Wesleyan - Alpha Delta Phi Agreements
    - Dining, 1997-2005 (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - Dumpster, 2003 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - Program Housing, 1999 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Fraternity Standards, 2011 (Box 179, Folder 5-6)
  - Board of House Presidents, 1977-1983 (Box 179, Folder 7-8)
  - Fraternity Relations, 1946-2005 (Box 179, Folder 9)
  - Fraternity Relations, 1961-1969 (Box 179, Folder 10-11)
  - Fraternity Relations, 1970-2005 (Box 180, Folder 1-4)
  - Reunion, 2002-2006 (Box 180, Folder 5-9)
  - Reunion, 1998 (Box 180, Folder 10)
  - Reunion, 1975 (Box 180, Folder 11)
- Series XIV: Publications 1832-2008
  This series includes publications other than songbooks of Alpha Delta Phi International and/or the Middletown Chapter and Wesleyan University publications. Materials for this series are housed in six document boxes and seven custom boxes, 3.2 linear feet.
  - Alpha Delta Phi Publications
    - AdLit, 1967-1970 Spring (Box 180, Folder 12-13)
    - AdLit, 1974-1985 Winter (Box 181, Folder 1-13)
    - AdLit, 1986 Spring-2005 Fall (Box 182, Folder 1-11)
    - AdLit, Prose & Poetry, 2006 Spring (Box 182, Folder 12)
    - AdLit, Photography, 2006 Spring (Box 182, Folder 13)
    - AdLit, Prose & Poetry, 2007 Spring (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - AdLit, 2008 Spring (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Catalogue
      - Alumni Record, 1856-1880 (Box 184)
      - The Alpha Delta Phi, 1832-1882 (Box 185)
      - 1879 (Box 183, Folder 3)
      - 1909 (Box 183, Folder 4)
      - 1936 (Box 183, Folder 5)
      - 1956, 1966, 1982 (Box 186)
      - 2002 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Memorial of Samuel Eells, 1873 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - Sesquicentennial Celebration, 2006 (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Star & Crecent, 1884, undated (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - Star & Crecent, Vol. I, bound with Wesleyan Argus, Vol. 14, 1880-1881 (Box 188)
    - Star & Crecent, Vol. II-Vol. III, 1881-1883 (Box 188)
    - Guide to the Archives, Sesquicentennial Celebration (Box 188)
  - Miscellaneous Publications
    - Stillborn, undated (Box 187, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan University Publications
    - Olla Podrida (annotated), 1995 (Box 187, Folder 6)
    - Wesleyan Verse, 1914 (Box 187, Folder 7)